Guide to the Vassar College Goodfellowship Club Records, 1902-1957
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Goodfellowship Club Records
1902-1957
Vassar College Goodfellowship Club
3.1 cubic feet (15 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials related to the Vassar College Goodfellowship Club, including correspondence, business papers and photographs.
Administrative History
The Steadfast Club was Vassar's first club of maids, students, and faculty, but it was short-lived, meeting from 1890-1891. In the spring of 1901, the Vassar Students' Association developed an idea to found a social center for the workers in the housekeeping department. In 1902-1903, the Good Fellowship Club (later the Goodfellowship Club) was organized. The Trustees approved the idea for the construction of a building in June, 1903, and the students proceeded to raise $10,000 in order to build the building
The Maids' Club-house, home of the Goodfellowship Club, opened in March, 1908. The Club-house included a circulating library, a sewing machine, a laundry room, dining room, kitchen, and infirmary. The Club sponsored evening classes (recreational, domestic, and academic), and cultural events. One paid dues in order to belong. With the rise of unions after World War II, the Club eventually dwindled in membership and passed out of existence.
Scope and Content Note
The Vassar College Goodfellowship Club Records include reports, correspondence, members' organization notebooks, publications, notes on miscellaneous club activities and photographs.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Societies and clubs
Subjects:
Housekeepers--Societies and clubs; Student organizations--United States
VCL Categories
Vassar College Campus Organizations
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 17 Mar 2009.
Series List
- Series I. Constitution and History, 1902-1957; (Boxes 1-2)
- Series II. Club Reports, 1908-1954; (Boxes 3-6)
- Series III. Notebooks, 1908-1938; (Boxes 7-10)
- Series IV. Correspondence, 1909-1943; (Box 11)
- Series V. Activities and Publications, 1907-1942; (Boxes 12-13)
- Series VI. Photographs, (Box 14)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous, (Box 15)
Container List
- SERIES I. Constitution and History, 1902-1957
  - Constitution of Goodfellowship Club (Folder 1.1)
  - Constitution of Goodfellowship Club (Folder 1.2)
  - History of the Maids' Club House of Vassar College, 1912 (Folder 1.3)
  - Visitors of the Maids' Club House, 1908-1957 (Folder 1.4)
  - Chart of History of Goodfellowship Club House (Folder 1.5)
  - The Yearbook of The Goodfellowship Club, 1910 (Folder 2.1)
  - The Yearbook of The Goodfellowship Club, 1911 (Folder 2.2)
- SERIES II. Club Reports, 1908-1954
  - Club Reports, 1911-1934 (Folder 3.1)
  - Club Reports, 1935-1941 (Folder 3.2)
  - Club House Reports, 1911-1912, 1916-1917, 1917-1918 (Folder 3.3)
  - Club House Reports, 1914-1915 (Folder 3.4)
  - Club House Reports, 1914-1915 (Folder 3.5)
  - Club House Reports, 1915-1916 (Folder 3.6)
  - Club House Reports, 1913, 1918, 1923-1926, 1930-1931 (Folder 3.7)
  - Club House Reports, 1931-1943 (Folder 4.1)
  - Goodfellowship Club House Reports, 1922-1924 (Folder 4.2)
  - Goodfellowship Club Reports, [1922-1954] (Folder 4.3)
  - Miscellaneous Reports: Ruth Cutler, 1911-1912 (Folder 4.4)
  - Sub-Chairmen Reports, 1912-1913 (Folder 4.4)
  - Committee Reports, 1926-1927 (Folder 5.1)
  - Committee Reports, 1927-1928 (Folder 5.2)
  - Reports to Students' Association, 1911-1912, 1912-1913 (Folder 5.3)
  - Report of the House Committee, 1912-1913 (Folder 5.4)
  - Report to the Students' Association: Evelyn Noble, 1912-1913 (Folder 5.4)
  - Supervisor's Reports, 1913, 1921-1922 (Folder 5.5)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1913 (Folder 5.6)
  - Goodfellowship Club Records of Business Meetings by Secretary, 1908-1910 (Folder 5.7)
  - Goodfellowship Accounts, 1941-1944 (Folder 6.1)
  - Goodfellowship Club Accounts, 1934/1935-1937/1938 (Folder 6.2)
  - Goodfellowship Club Accounts, 1938/1938-1940/1941 (Folder 6.3)
- SERIES III. Notebooks, 1908-1938
  - Ring binder: pages taken from a scrapbook from the Good Fellowship Club House, 1908-1910 (Box 7)
  - Club House Notebook: Ruth Cutler, 1910-1911 (Folder 8.1)
  - Club House Notebook: Ruth Cutler, 1910-1911 (Folder 8.2)
  - Club House Notebook: Ruth Cutler, 1911-1912 (Folder 8.3)
  - Club House Notebook: Ruth Cutler, 1911-1912 (Folder 8.4)
  - Club House Notebooks: Evelyn Noble, 1912-1913 (Folder 8.5)
  - Chairman's Notebook: Evelyn Noble, 1912-1913 (Folder 9.1)
  - Club House Committee Notes: Adeline De Sale, Secretary, 1912-1913 (Folder 9.1)
  - Chairman's Notebook: Evelyn Noble, 1912-1913 (Folder 9.2)
  - Club House Notebook, 1913-1914 (Folder 9.3)
  - Chairman's Notes: Anne Thorpe, 1915-1916 (Folder 9.4)
  - Chairman's Notebook: Constance Woodworth, 1926-1928 (Folder 9.5)
  - Chairman's Notebook: Kathleen B. Smyth, 1928-1930 (Folder 10.1)
  - Chairman's Notebook: Kathleen B. Smyth, 1928-1930 (Folder 10.2)
  - Goodfellowship Club Plays Notebook, 1930-1938 (Folder 10.3)
- SERIES IV. Correspondence, 1909-1943
  - To Club House/Club House News (General) (Folder 11.1)
  - From Club House/Club House News (Folder 11.2)
  - Regarding endowment funds, 1909-1910 (Folder 11.3)
  - Regarding endowment funds, 1911, 1912, 1923 (Folder 11.4)
  - Letters and Notes, 1914-1943 (Folder 11.5)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Folder 11.6)
- SERIES V. Activities and Publications, 1907-1942
  - Chart of Goodfellowship Club House Activities, 1907-1915 (Folder 12.1)
  - Activities, 1911-1914 (Folder 12.2)
  - Activities, 1925-1925 (Folder 12.3)
  - Activities, 1936-1942, 1950, undated (Folder 12.4)
  - Red Cross-First Aid Courses (Folder 12.5)
  - Swimming-Kenyon Gym, 9 Oct 1934 (Folder 12.6)
  - Productions: The Love Doctor and The Birds' Christmas Carol (Folder 12.7)
  - Productions: The Travel Class (Folder 12.8)
  - Productions: Three Cornered Moon, 1941 (Folder 12.9)
  - Club House News Scrapbook, 1925-1926 (Folder 12.10)
  - Club House News, 1920-1921 (Folder 13.1)
  - Club House News, 1921-1924 (Folder 13.2)
  - Club House News, 1925-1928 (Folder 13.3)
  - Club House News, 1929-1933 (Folder 13.4)
  - Club House News, 1934-1937 (Folder 13.5)
  - Club House News, 1939-1940 (Folder 13.5)
- SERIES VI. Photographs
  - Photographs of Club House Building (Folder 14.1)
  - Photographs of Goodfellowship Club members and productions (Folder 14.2)
  - Photographs and theatrical productions (Folder 14.3)
  - Photographs, miscellaneous (Folder 14.4)
  - Photograph Album, circa 1920-1929 (Folder 14.5)
- SERIES VII. Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous club information; press releases; club history; articles (Folder 15.1)
  - Good Fellowship Club, miscellaneous (Folder 15.2)
  - Employee fire Capts. Black out, etc. (Folder 15.3)
  - Employee 75th Benefit, 1940 (Folder 15.4)
  - Lists, Notices (Folder 15.5)
  - Membership List, 1936-1937 (Folder 15.6)
  - Club House Council; Student Committee [list of members], 1932/1933-1937/1938 (Folder 15.7)
  - Vassar Drive, 1933-1946 (Folder 15.8)